The Bog has already swallowed half of Kaiji's money—25 million yen!
すでに軍資金の半分2500万が
沼にのみ込まれたカイジ
Still, he continues!
だが つぎ込む
カイジ　ひたすらつぎ込む
Kaiji continues intently!
Iron Gate
Before he even notices it, Kaiji's wish, his prayer...
気がつくとカイジの願い 悲願が…
ドア…
声に 言葉になる！
The door...
Escapes his lips!
Open! Open!
開け 開け 開け！ドア！
Open, door!
開け！開かれろ！ドア！
Open!
Open up, door!
アラビアンナイトの
アリババと盗賊の話だっけ？
What's this supposed to be, the story of Ali Baba and the Forty Thieves?
開けゴマとか抜かして
開いた扉の向こうに
Do you really think you can open the door to fabulous riches just by shouting "open sesame?"
金銀財宝の山が
あったっていうのは
しかし残念ながら
そんなことは おとぎ話の中の話
Sadly for you, that kind of thing only happens in fairy tales.
In this world, there are no magic or miracles.
ありゃしねえんだよ
この世には魔法も呪文も
そろそろ切り上げどころ
じゃないのかな？カイジ君
It's it about time you just gave up?
I'm certainly glad to take your money, but you're not doing yourself any good here.
散財してくれるのは ありがたいが
あまりに空しく
カイジ君の金が消えるのも
I feel sorry for you, so I don't want to watch you force yourself into it.
ふびんというか
さすがに忍びなくてね ハハハ…
ああっ！あっ ああ…
And sadly, it doesn't matter how many you shoot.
な？空しいだろ？
何度打っても もう
いや　そうでもねえ
ああ？
No! That's wrong!
No! I'm not wasting my time!
空しくはねえ　ここから
き… きとるのか？何か兆候が
Have you seen some kind of sign!?
ああ 実りつつある　ノックが
Yeah. My knocking's starting to get somewhere.
おお！
開く！開くぞ ドアが！
It's opening! The door's opening!
ああ？ドアが開く？
The door's opening?
よし いけ！いけ！いけ！
All right! Go for it!
Go! Go!
何のことだ？
What is he talking about?
もう少し　もう少しだ！
A little more! Just a little bit more!
何だ？何をそんなに騒いでる
What? What's gotten into him?
別に変わったことは何も…
Nothing's changed at all!
きた きた きた！
ついにきたぞ クルーンに！
Here we go!
He's made it to the trays!
えっ？な… 何だ？
What!?
He's in the trays!
入ったのか？クルーンに
Wow, he made it!
ほんとだ！入ってる！
どうやって？
How'd he do it!?
He went straight through!
真っすぐだ　真っすぐ入った！
村上！ど… どうしてだ？
Murakami! How'd he do it!?
閉じるタイミングは
コンピューターが…
The flipper timing's supposed to be computer-controlled!
あっ ああ　て… 店長！
Boss!
ああ！何！
What!?
Impossible! They're not closing!
バカな！
閉じ切っていないじゃないか！
ガバガバだ　役をなしてない
The gap's too big! They can't block the balls!
They're just helping it in!
これじゃ まるでザル
きた きた
いけ いけ！
Here we go!
Go for it!
どういうことだ…
水も漏らさぬ不可侵の砦
What's going on!? That barrier's supposed to be impervious! Airtight!
あの鉄壁の門が閉まらないなんて
Yet it can't even close!
これじゃ閉まるはずがない
ダメだ！
It can't hold off anything anymore!
この門では もう
敵の侵入 侵略を…
The enemy's attack— Their invasion—
It's useless! It's smashed!
防げない… 決壊
バカな　何だ これは
あり得ない！
Why!? This is impossible!
フフフ　それにしても こいつ
He thought up something unbelievable.
とんでもないことを
思いつきやがる
分かってんのか？敵はあの城門を
自在にｺﾝﾋﾟｭｰﾀｰ制御できるんだぜ
You know those flippers are computer-controlled, right?
遠藤さん　関係ないんすよ
I don't care, Endoh.
It doesn't matter how they control it if I crush them.
制御もクソも　クラッシュ
ぶっ壊しちまえばいいんですよ
根本から
ぶっ壊す？
Crush them?
説明します　あの役モノは
Here, I'll explain.
The flippers are pushed by these shafts.
ここの支柱が動いて
開閉してるんです
ですから そこがヘタれば
役をなさなくなる
Bend them, and they won't close.
しかし ヘタると言っても…
And how are we supposed to do that?
We melt them, with this.
溶かします　こいつで
えっ？カイロ？
A hand warmer?
Yeah. The second you break the vacuum seal on a disposable hand warmer,
ええ　使い捨てカイロは
真空パックの袋を破った瞬間に
空気に触れて鉄が酸化し
熱の放射発生が始まる
the iron inside begins to oxidize and produce heat.
We scale that down and hide it in the shaft.
この原理を
そのままミニサイズにして
こんなふうに
役モノの支えの部分に仕込む
But then we can't break the seal directly.
でも仕込んだ真空パックの袋は
直接 破ることはできないので
こんぺいとうのような
ギザギザのある玉を
We need to sneak in balls covered in tiny spikes too.
隣に仕込んでおきます
そうすれば役モノが動くたびに
真空パックをノックし続け
If we do that, then every time I take a shot, it'll knock on the vacuum pack.
ある回数を超えたら袋は破れ
Shoot enough times, and the iron will start to oxidize—it'll heat up.
鉄の酸化 すなわち
熱が発生し始める
And the shaft will melt from within.
結果 その支柱を内部から溶かす
だが少量だろ 中に仕込める鉄粉は
But we can't fit much iron powder in the shaft.
当然 発生する熱も少量
I can't get all that hot. Will it be enough to melt the plastic?
そんなもんで溶かせんのか？
支柱のプラスチックを
おっしゃる通りです
この程度の熱では無理
You're right. It won't be hot enough.
でも変えればいいんです
一部分でもいいから別の素材に
But change the material we're working with...
I think this will work.
それには これが効果的です
ああ… 何だ？それ
What's that?
ああ？
サッカロイドの凝固形
Crystallized saccharide. That is, candy.
つまりアメです
Candy?
アメ？
一部分とはいえ
If we replace part of the shaft with a material which melts easily, it'll warp.
熱に弱い素材を仕込めば
あの支えの部品はヘタる
しかもそのヘタリは
打ってすぐじゃなく
And it won't happen right after it's hit. It'll take a while.
ある程度 時間を経た後
１時間ぐらいは打った後に
壊れてくれないと困る
We need it to take an hour or so of being hit.
Otherwise they'll pick up on it while testing the machine before we even show up.
でないと勝負前の試し打ちや
俺たちが勝負に行く前に
誰かが打ち出してヘタったら
話にならない
だがどうやって その仕掛けを
仕込む？すり替える？
But how do we get it in? How do we swap them?
あの沼は24時間
厳重に監視されてるんだぜ
They've got the Bog on camera 24/7.
確かに通常の状態では
一分の隙もない
Normally, we'd have no chance.
しかし何らかの理由で
沼の部品が破損
But what if the Bog's damaged for some reason?
もしくは故障した時
敵はどうすると思います？
What do you think they do when it breaks down?
They send it to the manufacturer for repairs!
外部に注文するんですよ
沼の製造元に
その工場が部品の修理を終え
カジノに納品するまで
It's completely out of their hands until it comes back!
敵はまったくノータッチ
管轄外ってやつで
It's out of their control! Their guard's down!
警戒ゼロ　ノーガード
So let's not sweat the little things! Let's just smash the machine!
要するに細かい話は抜きで
壊しちまえばいいんですよ 台を
And I know just the man.
幸いなことに約１名
恨み骨髄　あの沼を叩き壊すに
He holds enough of a grudge.
He has plenty of reason to smash the Bog.
十分な理由を持つ男を
知っています
We get him to smash the Bog, and have the parts swapped in by the repairman.
その男に台を壊させ
修理を頼まれた工場が
新しい部品を納品する前に
すり替えておく
前もって用意した
時限破壊装置入りの
These special self-destructing flippers.
このスペシャル役モノを
Think it'll work?
どうです？いい計画でしょ？
たぶん失敗するな それ
えっ？
Not really.
さっき｢壊すのに十分な恨み｣って
言ったが
You say he's got enough of a grudge to smash it,
but it'll look pretty forced.
もう その辺りからウソくせえ
プンプン臭うだろ
They'll think the whole thing stinks.
何か納得のいかない空気 違和感が
どうしたって引っかかる
なんで壊すんだと？
They won't be able to figure it out.
Why would he smash it?
What would he be doing that for? Anger? Resentment?
壊して何になる？怒り 恨み
Those won't be enough to make him do it.
そんなことで
こんな大それたことするか？
He'd have to have a different reason.
となると当然 何か別の理由が
あるんじゃないかと考える
でも遠藤さん
その違和感っていう引っかかり
We can use that suspicion.
結構 使えるんですよ
ああ？
Remember, bones are strongest where they've broken before.
言うじゃないですか
骨は折れてくっついたところが
一番 強くなるって
つまり うまく使えば
その違和感こそ強力な接着剤
If we do this right, that suspicion will hold everything together.
That's the trick, the genius, of my plan.
今回の仕事を仕上げる隠し味 妙趣
沼の大騒ぎが
さしたる疑いも呼ばず
We're worse off if we don't make a scene and just sit there taking it.
スッと通過しちまったら
むしろ そっちのほうが怖い
その時は感じずとも
心の深い消化不良というか
If we don't, Ichijou's stomach will start to turn.
くすぶり続けます　消えぬ疑念が
He'll begin to worry.
So make a scene, and then he's relieved when it comes to nothing.
むしろ一度疑わせ それを解決
消化させてやるのが うまい手
フフ　残念だったな
I'm sorry. Did you find what you were looking for?
で 見つかったかい？
お目当てのものは
We give him exactly what he was expecting!
与えてやればいい
敵が納得のいく理由 解決を
Is this what you were after?
これが狙いだったんだろ？
自分が頭が切れると
思ってる奴ほど
He thinks he's clever. We can use that to trick him.
この解決 消化の心理の穴
仕組みにハマっちまう
Don't worry. This will take all the suspicion off us.
安心してください
見事 脱臭してみせますよ
That "stink" you were talking about will be gone.
遠藤さんが言うところの
ウソ臭さを
脱臭か　大したもんだ
Remove the stink, huh...
You did a damn good job of that.
消したんだな　見事 臭いを
And now you've got that nancy Ichijou off balance!
そして出し抜いた
あの細心で用心深い一条を
時間はかかったが第２関門も突破
It took a while, but the second gate's fallen.
残るはクルーン
All that's left is the trays!
あのクルーンだけだ！
Nothing but the trays!
フッ 言われずとも いくさ
You don't even need to tell me! There's nowhere to go from here but up!
ここで いかずにどうする
This is a once-in-a-lifetime chance!
こんな千載一遇の…
終わりか　３枚目も
I'm not gonna quit after three cards!
ああ！いいところなのに
It was just getting good!
まだ続けるよな？
You think he's gonna keep going?
でも もう3000万も使ってんだぜ
He's gone through 30 mil already...
I've still got twenty.
あるさ　まだ2000万
すげえ！すげえ！
Holy shit!
Man, if I quit here I'd never forgive myself.
当然さ　ここでガス欠ってんじゃ
泣いても泣き切れねえ
やっと女神が
ほほえんだってのによ
I can't let down Lady Luck now that she's smiling!
Yeah!
そうだ そうだ！
いけ いけ！
Go for it!
1000万だ　とりあえず
うっ…
Another 10 mil for now.
Hurry it up, I'm gonna lose my flow.
さっさとしな！グズグズされちゃ
流れが切れる
待て ここまでだ　勝負は中止！
Wait!
No more! You're finished!
I won't let you buy any more Paqy!
これ以上のパッキーの購入は
認めない！
はあ？
はあじゃない
Don't just give me that blank stare! Everyone can see what's going on!
見ろ　誰が見たって
もう続けられる状態じゃあるまい
Really?
そうか？構わないぜ 俺は別に
I don't really give a shit.
うっ… ふざけるな
Don't fuck around!
I'm not trying to fuck around, it just comes naturally.
ふざけてなんかいないさ
神様のおぼしめしで今
クルーンにフリーパス
God's just blessed me with a free pass to the trays.
I need to take advantage of my good luck.
この幸運を生かさないとな
ぐっ… 貴様
You son of a bitch!
Come on, Ichijou. This kind of problem is your fault.
一条　言っとくがな
この破損 アクシデントは
そっちのミス
責任 不備 関係ねえんだぜ
打ち手の俺には
Don't hate the player. Hate the game.
Doesn't it say so right on that sign?
あそこの ただし書きにも
あるじゃないか
Once someone starts playing, nothing gets changed behind the glass.
｢一度 打ち始めたら
どんな不都合が起ころうとも｣
｢ガラス戸を開けての
クギ調整等の操作｣
｢変更はしない｣と
バカ！よく読んでみろ
Idiot! Read the rest!
書いてあるだろうが！
好きなだけ遊んでいいが
It says you can play as much as you like, only as long as you're not cheating!
ただしゴト行為があった場合は
別だと
ゴト？
とぼけるな
Cheating?
Don't play dumb! It's obvious!
明らかじゃないか
６日前の大暴れ
You swapped something in while the Bog was being repaired after you broke it!
あれでこの沼を壊し
修理に出した部品をすり替えた
どんな細工か知らんが
何かを仕組んだ！
I don't know how you did it, but you did it!
その偽物に！違うか！
It's a fake! We both know it!
フフ　何を言い出すと思ったら
Of all the things for you to say...
臆測だろ　今言ったことすべて
You're just guessing!
ぐっ…
何一つないだろ？
You have absolutely no proof that the old man or I did that!
俺やおっちゃんが
そんなことしたって証拠
黙れ 黙れ 黙れ！
証拠もクソもあるか！
Shut up shut up shut up!
I don't need any proof!
そう考えるしかねえんだよ！
That's gotta be what happened!
After you smashed it like that, anyone would be sure!
その壊れ方は
誰がどう考えたって！
ハハ 一条　そんなのは通らない
Silly Ichijou. No one's going to believe that.
今やってるのは
1000円 2000円じゃない
We're not playing for thousands. We're playing for millions.
ウン千万 億っていうギャンブルだ
No one's going to stop a high-stakes game for that kind of guesswork.
そんな大勝負を不確かな臆測や
決めつけで中止なんてできない
うっ…
第一
Plus, you've had these flippers rigged anyway!
このクルーン前の門番に関しては
やってたよな？あんたら
間違いなく操作を
うっ… 何を言う！
What are you talking about!?
They're supposed to let one ball in three through, but how many have they stopped?
本来 ３分の１の確率で通る玉が
何回連続で この役モノに
止められたと思ってる？
200回は超えている
Over 200! Yet I've ignored it and kept playing.
しかし目をつぶってきただろ？
そのことについて俺は
ぐっ…
当然さ　仕方ないんだ
I don't even care.
Because I don't have any proof.
だって証拠がないんだもんな
証拠が
なら黙るしかない
So I just shut up. Because I'm serious.
それが真剣勝負ってもんだろ
ぐっ…
But here you are, letting people play when things go your way
それを自分に都合のいい時は
続行させておいて
and then shutting them down the second something you don't expect happens.
何かハプニング 不測の事態で
都合が悪くなると中止なんて
No one's gonna put up with that self-centered bullshit.
通るかよ！そんな自分勝手が！
Right, guys?
そうだろ？みんな
おお
そうだ！
その通りだ！
Yeah!
He's right!
We can see right through you!
見え見えだったぞ！
やらせろ！やらせろ！
Let him play!
He's playing the crowd...
くっ… こいつら調子に乗って…
て… 店長　電話ですが
Boss! Phone!
I don't have time for that right now! Tell him to call back later!
バカ！こんな時に！切れ！
But...
し… しかし…
Ichijou speaking.
はい　一条ですが
Just what is going on up there?
何なんだ 一体
おっ 誰だ？
Who's this!?
王国 王国帝愛グループの
幹部候補生ともあろう者が
I never expected this kind of behavior from a man tapped to join Teiai Group's management.
なんたる醜態だ
ああ… まさか その声は…
That voice...
Mr. Hyodo!
兵藤さま！
何？
What!?
か… 会長　一体…
Sir, what can I...
I've seen how powerless you are, Ichijou.
見ていた　一部始終を
力足らずが
Would you like to sleep with the fishes?
入るか？海に
Rot at the bottom of the sea?
深海に漂う藻くず よどみ
Sir!
会長…
はっ クズが
You're trash.
お恥ずかしいところをお見せして
申し訳ありません
I'm very sorry you had to see that!
Take this bet, Ichijou.
一条　受けてやれ
うーん　確かに奴が
その真ん中の役モノに
He may well have done something to the flippers.
何かを仕組んだのは明らかだ
今 台を開け
その部分を入念に調べれば
If you take apart the machine and go digging, you might a hint.
何かタネのようなものが
出てくるかもしれん
But that'd be all.
しかし そこまで
そのことと奴を結びつけるものが
とりあえずない
There's nothing to tie him to it.
とすると奴のゴトと
断定することはできない
So you can't prove he's cheating.
It's obvious that someone's cheating, so you can stop the game.
それでも何者かによるゴト行為が
発生したことは確かだから
中止 勝負取りやめということも
You can force him to stop, if you really want to.
強引ながら できないこともない
はい　ですから会長…
Of course! So, sir...
ただし それはこちらに
失点がない場合に限る
But only when we don't lose anything by doing so.
はっ？
下手クソが　なんて下手なんだ
You're such a fuckup.
見え見えじゃないか
お前の遠隔操作 ブロック
I've been watching your "block" and it's completely obvious.
With that kind of unfair trick going on, there's no way you can stop him playing.
そんな下手クソな不公平感が
吹き上がる見せ物をしていて
自分に不利な状況になったから
中止などと言えるわけもあるまい
You don't need to be fair, but you need to look fair.
公平である必要はないが
少なくとも
公平感は客に与えねばならんのだ
今日のお前の始末 やり方は下の下
Your performance today is the poorest I've seen in years.
そんなやり方では
At that rate, you'll never wring enough money out of them.
搾り取れんだろうが 下民どもから
はっ！す… すいません！
I'm sorry, sir!
So you need to let him play, so it doesn't look unfair.
だから受けてやれ
これ以上 客に不公平感を
持たせてはいかん
そんなことをすれば
沼だけの問題では済まず
If you cut him off, it'll reflect poorly on the casino and the whole of Teiai, not just the Bog.
カジノ全体 帝愛そのものへの
不信感につながる
You mustn't let that happen.
それだけは絶対に避けねばならん
帝愛は愛されねばならんのだ
Teiai must be well-loved to keep the cash flowing.
もっともっと金を得るために
は… はい！
だから
Of course!
So we have to let Kaiji finish himself off.
ここは潔くカイジの言い分を認め
その上で
殺せばよい　魔性３段クルーンで
In the Demonic Triple Tray...
うう…
それとも自信がないのか？
Or don't you have the trays rigged?
クルーン勝負
いえ！
I do, sir!
I thought those were your best work.
あれは
お前の自信作ではなかったのか？
信じられんのか？
自分を 自分自身を
Can't you believe in yourself?
いえ！そんなことはありません
That's not it, sir! The trays are impenetrable! I'm sure of it!
クルーンは絶対です
上りません！水は決して上へ！
フフフ　そうだ その意気だ
Excellent. That's what I want to hear.
戦え　そして勝て
Fight and win.
Or die.
あるいは死ね
えっ…
ハハハ　万が一の場合はな
Of course, I don't expect that to happen.
Boss!
て… 店長
Those trays went untouched!
クルーンは… あのクルーンは
手つかずのはず
All he smashed were the flippers in the middle!
この間の大暴れで破壊されたのは
真ん中の役モノだけ
クルーンは手つかず
交換もされてない
The trays were untouched! They didn't get replaced!
おい 村上
あっ はい
Hey, Murakami.
Yes?
例の役モノを交換する時
You were there when they swapped out the flippers, right?
お前 ついていたよな？
ええ
Yes.
その時 何か怪しい動きが
なかったか？
Did anything seem strange?
Did the repairman do anything to the trays?
その作業員がクルーンに
何か仕掛けるような
いえ　クルーンには
指一本 触れさせていません
No, sir! He didn't even touch them!
I checked them afterwards while I was testing it, and they were fine!
それに交換の後 試し打ちと共に
クルーンのチェックもしましたが
異常は認められませんでした
３段目もか？
もちろんです
The third tray too?
Of course! I really put that one through its paces!
３段目は特に入念にチェック
I tried with dozens of balls, and none made it through!
10 20と玉を入れ試しましたが
当たりは皆無
何の問題もありません
Good. Then there's no problem.
そうか　なら問題ない
As long as the trays are untouched, we can't lose!
クルーンに変化がない以上
敗北はない！
Hey!
おいおい！一体いつまで
待たせるつもりだ！
How long are you gonna keep us waiting!?
そうだ　さっさと始めろ！
Yeah! Let's get this started!
再開しろ 再開！
そうだ そうだ！
Let's go!
Come on!
分かりました
えっ？
Understood.
Don't worry. We would never get in the way of a game.
ご安心ください　当カジノは
逃げも隠れもいたしません
I'm sure you can see the terrible condition the machine's in,
ご覧のように台は壊滅的
ひどい惨状でありますが
この状態を引き起こしたのが
but I have no proof that Kaiji, the player, is behind it.
打ち手のカイジ君である確証が
ない以上
認めます　彼の続行を
おお！
So I'll let him continue playing.
やった！
All right!
村上
はっ
Murakami.
Yes.
今日は通常設定だろ？
Today's setting is normal, right?
Yes.
It's set to 5-5-5.
プラス５５５で
セットしておりますが
Change it to 7-7-7. Just to be safe.
念のため７７７にしろ
We can't let him hit the jackpot.
万が一にも突破は許されない
I'll kill him!
殺す！ここでカイジを殺す！
I'll kill him right here!
1000万パッキー
あと こいつが２枚
Ten million Paqy... I've got two of these left.
I've got to do it with these.
決まる　どうであれ これで
Here goes!
いくぜ！
おお！
All that's left is their last line of defense!
残るは敵の本丸
All that's left is the trays!
このクルーンだけ
It may be an impenetrable fortress,
難攻不落　鉄壁の城だが
but I have air superiority!
制空権は奪った
All they can do is look up at the sky!
空を見上げるだけさ 敵は
So I'll make it rain!
となりゃ降らせてやる
A rain of silver balls!
雨 銀玉の雨を！
爆撃だ！焼く　焼き尽くす！
I'll bomb them!
I'll burn them! Burn them down!
カイジ　第２関門も突破
Kaiji breaks through the second gate!
次なる難関 ３段クルーンは
さらに強敵
The next foe, the triple tray, is even fiercer!
命を懸けた死の攻防
Kaiji and Ichijou stake their lives on this battle!
Their battle continues beyond reason!
狂気の限界を超え 戦いは続く
続く！
It continues!
We can use that suspicion.
We're worse off if we don't make a scene and just sit there taking it.
We give him exactly what he was expecting!